doing to you, your body, chemistry and mind, and
you have a professional
supporting you, not only during the appointment,
together you can teach
your body to respond differently. I describe it
as a muscle: every time you
feel the trigger but do not react in the same
way, that muscle becomes stronger,
your danger threshold rises, and your body learns
that the alarm was unnecessary and you were not
in danger. It no longer needs to sound the alarm
or release all that chemistry,
or create such desperation. Little by little, we
change the pattern,
the neural pathways and your reactions. Like
everything else in
our body, we are neuroplastic, thankfully. This
pattern can change through
this process: strengthening the muscle, reducing
the sense of danger,
bringing safety and showing your body that
everything is all right. These
alarms gradually switch off, and you can feel
more in control,